## John Lai

Phone: 647-296-6528 | Email: lai.john.py@gmail.com | Toronto, Ontario LinkedIn:linkedin.com/in/johnxlai | GitHub:github.com/johnxlai | Portfolio: https://johnlai.ca/

#### About me

Web Developer with 5+ years in Front-End web development and design. Experienced with integrating creativity and solutions to build mobile-driven and user-friendly applications. Great attention to detail and unwavering commitment to precision, even when working on highly complex projects. Outside of work, I enjoy camping, fishing, problem-solving, and playing soccer competitively.

#### **Technical Skills**

**Technical Languages:** HTML5 / CSS3 / SASS / JavaScript / JSON / jQuery / APIs / REST API's / Jest / GraphQL / MongoDB / Mongoose / Express / React / Node / SQL / MySQL / NoSQL / WordPress / Tailwind / Bootstrap / Handlebars / TypeScript / Next.js

Applications & Tools: VS Code / Insomnia / Postman / Git / GitLab / GitHub / Figma / Adobe Illustrator / Photoshop / Sketch / MongoDB Compass & Altas / Heroku / Apollo / Jira / Terminal / Command Line Cli / Webpack / NPM / Yarn / Composer / Gulp / CMS / Firebase

#### **Experience**

Web Developer BlkBear Inc - Self-Employed May 2023 - Present Toronto

• Converted Photoshop, Sketch, and Figma designs into cross-browser compatible web pages or

- WordPress websites with accessibility functionalities (WCAG and ARIA)
  Collaborated with clients, designers, and developers to resolve client's issues within the deadline
- & and budgeted effort
- Developed and maintained responsive websites for entrepreneurs and small businesses

# Front-End Developer Carpages.ca

July 2015 – January 2023 Mississauga

- Developed and maintained responsive websites for 300+ car dealership clients using Bootstrap, Tailwind, Gemini (in-house framework) HTML5, CSS3, SASS, PHP (Twig), JavaScript, and jQuery for platinum clients: Ford, Hyundai, Toyota, Honda, Chrysler, and many more
- Written documentation to provide guidance to other team members for troubleshooting
- Experienced with bundling tools such as NPM, Yarn, Webpack, Grunt, and Gulp
- Used GIT version control to perform peer reviews for team members on merge requests to ensure clean codes are used
- Debug, modify, and reprogram JavaScript using Chrome development tool on branches via Gitlab to resolve client's issues within the deadline, and business requirements and according to functional specifications.

- Optimized website contents with Carpages API, ChromeData, Carfax, and Carguru plugins via Kanban board, Agile Development, and Scrum environment
- Integrated creative ideas with UX and graphic designers to build eye-catching websites, using gravity form, Advanced Custom Fields, and MigrateDB Databases
- Mentored and trained new developers via paired programming during onboarding and ensured their understanding of the product development lifecycle
- Ability to multitask, working on multiple projects while clearly communicating with stakeholders

## Web Content Design and Optimization Specialist Jonas Club Software

January 2013 - May 2015 Toronto

- Constructed and designed email marketing templates for leisure country clubs and yacht clubs across North America.
- Maintained website content for 200+ clients and performed content and layout adjustments using HTML, CSS, Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, and Dreamweaver.
- Applied Search Engine Optimization (SEO) best practices and provided technical assistance in a timely, professional manner.
- Managed multiple projects and participated in regular conference calls with clients to ensure deadlines were met.

Projects January - April 2023

FINGERSPELLING GAME | GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/johnxlai/asl-fingerspelling-game">https://github.com/johnxlai/asl-fingerspelling-game</a>
Live: <a href="https://tinyurl.com/asl-game">https://tinyurl.com/asl-game</a>

- A language learning web application for American sign language
- The application has the capability to compute level succession, store the number of games played, and highlight the last game and total scores for each player
- Used Kanban methodologies to plan, design, test, and execute all components of the project from interface, UX, Front-End to Back-End.
- Tech stacks used Node, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, UUID, Multer, Bcrypt, Handlebars, JavaScript, Tailwind, Heroku, JSON, and Git

ORACLE - AI FORTUNE TELLER | GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/johnxlai/oracle">https://github.com/johnxlai/oracle</a>

Live: <a href="http://tinyurl.com/oracle-online">http://tinyurl.com/oracle-online</a>

- Oracle is a major MERN full-stack project incorporating OpenAI to make predictions using Tarot Cards.
- Applied MERN stack technology and OpenAI to make future predictions, construct tarot card selection algorithm, OpenAI prompt worked with the online shop, Heroku, and MongoDB deployment
- Tech stacks used MongoDB, Express, React, Node, Apollo & GraphQl, OpenAI, Tailwind, Heroku, Git, Bcrypt, JavaScript, Jest, Tailwind, Stripe Payments, JSON

### **Education**

Full Stack Web Development Certificate: University of Toronto, Toronto Front-End Web Development Immersive Certificate: Juno College, Toronto

Web Optimization Analyst: Seneca College, Toronto

Advertising & Graphic Design Diploma: Humber College, Toronto Creative Advertising Diploma: Seneca at York University, Toronto